Moonjoo Kim | Software Developer

As a software developer with a strong focus on user experience and a knack for intricate problem-solving, I am committed to using my technical skills in programming to build web applications with APIs that improve users' quality of life. My positive, collaborative personality allows me to bring fresh perspectives and enthusiasm to every project, while my problem-solving skill enables me to devise inventive solutions that exceed expectations.

Technical Skills

Languages - JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON

Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api, Software Testing

Libraries and Frameworks - React, Next.js, Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap

Interpersonal Skills - Highly collaborative, problem solving, organizational, strong communicator, project management

Software Development Projects

Pineapple-Admin | Next.js, MongoDB, AWS (Full-Stack)

04/2023

Full-stack application that lets admin login and perform full CRUD with products for the ecommerce website.

- Made successful user authentication using **NextAuth.js** allowing admin to login using their Google account.
- Made RESTful API fetch calls to backend built with Nextjs and MongoDB handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations with the models.
- Created multiple models (products, categories, orders) and related them using MongoDB.
- Created the frontend also using **Nextjs** and styled with **Tailwind CSS**.
- Used AWS (Amazon Web Services) S3 Bucket to hold the images the admin uploads.

Pineapple-Front | Next.js, MongoDB, Stripe (Frontend)

04/2023

Apple clone e-commerce application that lets users view, add to cart, and purchase products.

- Made successful user authentication using NextAuth.js allowing admin to login using their Google account.
- Used Nextjs to fetch data the admin uploaded using the admin panel (Pineapple-admin) from MongoDB.
- Created the frontend also using Nextjs and plain CSS.
- Successfully used Stripe for the users to make payments.

Stackbook | MERN Stack (Frontend/Backend)

04/2023

Responsive full-stack social media group project that lets users create, delete, edit, and like posts using React.js.

- Made **RESTful API** fetch calls to an **Express, MongoDB, Node.js** backend with two models handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using **Postman**.
- Made successful user authentication using JWT token, Bcrypt, and react-router to allow users to register and login.
- Created the frontend using **React.js** and **Axios** to make API fetch calls.
- Collaborated with a fellow software engineer on GitHub, utilizing multiple branches and making pull requests.

Professional Experience

Research Assistant - Applied Metabolism and Physiology Research Lab | New Brunswick, NJ

02/2022 - 05/2022

- Maintained accurate and detail-oriented records of experimental procedures, data, and results using laboratory information management systems and spreadsheets for 50 participants during this internship.
- Supervised exercise sessions for study participants, ensuring that exercise protocols were properly implemented.
- Fostered a comfortable and supportive environment for study participants by engaging in small-talk and building rapport, which helped to reduce stress and anxiety.

5th Grade Instructor - Zenith Academy | Remote

09/2022 - 05/2023

- Delivering virtual instruction to a class of 5th grade students in reading, writing, and math via Zoom, using a variety of instructional strategies and tools to engage students in active learning.
- Incorporating technology and multimedia resources, such as interactive whiteboards and educational apps, to enhance the learning experience for students.
- Demonstrating a strong commitment to student success, and to creating a safe and welcoming learning environment that inspires a love of learning in all students.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

02/2023 - 05/2023

Graduation: May 2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Rutgers University | New Brunswick, New Jersey Bachelor of Science - Kinesiology